# **VOVA USHENKO**

# Web Developer

1509 14 Avenue Southwest D, Calgary, AB T3C 0W4, Canada

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a developer driven by the **quality of code** and software. I continuously strive to improve myself and always seek new challenges in creating, deploying and supporting new and existing applications and systems in a suitable environment

I have created **full-stack projects** with React and Node.js. Have excellent knowledge of modern JS stack for building complex user interfaces for the web platform.

I have a strong passion to build **elegant**, **performant and user-friendly experiences**. For the last 2 years I mostly worked with **the React stack** and building products from the ground up, including collecting business requirements, composing full-featured UX designs and architecting frontends.

A **teacher** at heart, I have been fortunate enough to pass what little I know to many people, thanks to my professional and volunteer activity. I have experience teaching software engineering at a University and being a mentor.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Master of Computer Engineering,**

*Advanced Computer Networks* Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv

#### **Bachelor of Computer Engineering**

Computer Networking, Cybersecurity and Telecommunication systems
Chernivtsi National University

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **Developer / Designer**

Chernivtsi National University, Ukraine 2017- present

Learning and expanding my skills in web development, I have supervised several projects and websites for the University.

- Developed and designed the Web portal using the MERN stack, including autentication and database backup
- Provided training including troubleshooting on the proper use of web technologies.
- Tested, updated, and maintained the website as well as the application throughout the website lifecycle
- Address and fix issues in a timely manner while keeping abreast on current and emerging technologies, standards, and trends.

# professional portfolio - vovaushenko.dev

in linkedin.com/in/vovau volodymyr.ushenko@gmail.com

github.com/vovaushenko 🔇 +1 5874386646

#### **KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **Frontend**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks: React, Next.js

Libraries: Redux, Redux-thunk, Redux-saga, MobX, Styled-components, SASS,

React-router, Material UI

Testing: TDD with Mocha, Jest and Enzyme

Tools: Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Git, Figma, Adobe Photoshop

#### **Backend**

Languages: Node.js (JavaScript, TypeScript), Python

**Frameworks**: Express, Next.js, NestJS **Web**: REST, JSON, GraphQL, WebSockets **Databases**: MongoDB with mongoose, MySQL

**Deployment**: Netlify, Heroku, AWS **Code Management**: Git, GitHub, GitLab

#### HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

#### **Professional Portfolio**

2020 - present

A personal portfolio built to showcase my genuine passion for webdevelopment and a small part of my professional skills. Built with React, Node and Love.

Technologies: React, ContextAPI, CSS-in-JS, Lazy Loading, Custom Hooks, Light/Dark Mode

## Coffee-shop MERN

2020-present

A real-world full-stack project with REST API, Node.js and JWT-authentication. The front-end part is written by using React with React Hooks, Redux and Redux Middlewares.

Technologies: React, Redux, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, React-Bootstrap, REST API

#### **Retrofit Online Commerce Platform**

2020-present

A custom eCommerce platform built with React, Context API, Node.js, Auth0 and Netlify Serverless Functions. This online furniture store has user authentication, stripe payment system and advanced product filtering.

Technologies: React, ContextAPI, Node.js, Serverless functions, CSS-in-

JS, Auth0

#### **Cocktail DB**

2020-present

A modern cocktail application written with React/Redux and enhanced with Typescript. The app features: Async Requests, Custom Redux Middleware, Action Cancellation, Lazy Loading, Client-Side Storage, Dark/Light mode.

Technologies: Typescript, React, Redux, CSS-in-JS, Redux Thunk, Custom Hooks